准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
球星珍珍
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
客串
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
高中
你们好
Ahoy there
让一让
Make way
借过一下
Coming through
那边有三个空位
There's room for three right there
谢谢你帮我们买票
Thanks for getting us tickets
来看盛大的比赛  蟹老板
to the big game, Mr. Krabs
说到这个
Speaking of
对了
Oh, yeah
这是我们欠你的钱
Here's what we owe ya
没问题  小子
Not a problem, boy-o
当然了  还记得我为什么邀请你吗
Of course, you do remember why I invited you?
肯定记得啊
Absolutely
我们要来支持珍珍
We're here to back Pearl up
到时候做你编的蟹堡王秘密啦啦操
when she does the secret Krusty Krab cheer you wrote
没错
Exactly
看看这边这么多人
Look how many people are here
免费打广告最划算了
You can't beat free advertisin'
等不及了
I can't wait
我从小就梦想着要做一个啦啦队员
Ever since I was a little sponge
it's been my dream to be a cheerleader
我从两秒钟前
Ever since two seconds ago
就梦想着要找到厕所
it's been my dream to find a toilet
憋住小便最最差
Holding it is the worst
派大星膀胱会爆炸
Patrick's bladder's gonna burst
加油  派大星
Go, Patrick
不过你进厕所前最好先别炸
But not before you get to the bathroom
你这操做得好  小子
That's good stuff, boy-o, good stuff
不过还是等打广告再做吧
But save it for the advertisement
这附近肯定有厕所
There's gotta be a bathroom around here somewhere
总算能舒坦地解手了
Sweet release
给我出去
Get out of here
这里可是解说间
This is the announcer's booth
那我就宣布我要解手
Well, I'm announcing that I have to tinkle
解 说
转下身
Turn around
你一直看  我尿不出来
I can't go if you're watching
住手
Stop
不要
No
好耶
Yes
天啊  比赛就要开始了
Oh, boy, the game's about to start
啦啦队员上场了
And here come the cheerleaders
珍珍肯定等不及要做我编的啦啦操了
I'll bet Pearl can't wait to do my cheer
加油  藤壶队
Let's go, Barnacles
啦啦啦
Rah-rah-rah
乖女儿珍珍
Pearly-girl
准备好帮老爸促销蟹黄堡了没
Ready to help Daddy sell some patties?
啦啦啦
Rah-rah-rah
一飞冲天
Sis-boom-bah
她好像没听到  蟹老板
I don't think she heard you, Mr. K
没事
Don't you worry
我来引起她的注意
I'll get her attention
女士们先鱼们
Ladies and gentlefish
比赛就要开场了
the game is about to begin
大家做好准备
so let's get ready
为我们的裤头村藤壶队加油吧
to cheer for our own Bikini Bottom Barnacles
顺便给我排空的膀胱加油
And cheer for my empty bladder
你怎么还不走
Why are you still here?
别碰话筒
Get off the mic
好耶
Yeah
触地得分
Touchdown
这可开了个坏头
That is not a good start
这比赛要打很久的  对吧
Well, it's a long game, right?
有得是时间可以扳回一城
Plenty of time for a comeback
这运气可不好
That is some bad luck
他摔倒了
He fell down
好个擒杀
What a sack
袋
没照着他们的意愿走
That didn't go their way
我都想吃蝴蝶脆饼了
I could go for a pretzel
我也是
Me too
加油  藤壶队
Let's go, Barnacles
啦啦啦
Rah-rah-rah
一飞冲天
Sis-boom-bah
啦啦啦
Rah-rah-rah
一飞冲天
Sis-boom-bah
派大星  比赛进展很不顺利
You know, Patrick, this game is going so poorly
我都想不到还能怎么形容不顺利了
I'm running out of ways to say "it's going poorly"
那了得起怎么样  帕奇
How about "badtastic," Perch?
我喜欢
I like it
主队的战况极度了得起
This is going extremely badtastic for the home team
他们只落后一分简直是奇迹
It's a miracle they're only down by one point
姐妹们  听好
Alright, girls, listen up
我们队还有机会赢
Our team can still win
但还需要有特别的东西来激励他们
but they need something special to get them motivated
他们需要
They need
终极啦啦操
the ultimate cheer
可是珍珍
But, Pearl
我们做终极啦啦操从来就没成功过
we've never successfully done the ultimate cheer
上次我们做了  害贝姬现在都没康复
Becky still hasn't recovered
from the last time we tried it
我们能行的  米齐
We can do it, Mitzy
我们一定行
I know we can
为了团队  不做也得做
We have to, for the team
加油  藤壶队
Go, Barnacles
搞破坏
Wrack 'em up
摞起来
Stack 'em up
高高叠罗汉
Pile 'em to the sky
加油  藤壶队
Let's go, Barnacles
决一死战
Do or die
我的天啊  我们成功了
Holy moly, we did it
小子看
Look, boy-o
大家目光都聚焦在啦啦队员身上了
Everyone's eyes are on the cheerleaders
现在正好可以来做我的蟹堡王啦啦操
Now's the perfect time for me Krusty Krab cheer
珍珍
Pearl
执行蟹黄堡宣传行动
Commence Operation Patty Plug
蟹黄堡儿真美味
Krabby Patties, taste so great
蟹黄堡儿买八个才对
Krabby Patties, you must buy eight
蟹堡王
简直不可思议  各位
This is unbelievable, folks
但有一个啦啦队员似乎
but a cheerleader appears
被橄榄球堵住了呼吸孔
to have the football stuck in her blowhole
而且比赛还在继续
and the play is still going
是那个触地得那啥
It's one of those touchy-downy things
还更好呢
Even better
是胜利的触地得那啥
It was the winning touchy-downy
应该是  触地得分
I mean, touchdown
藤壶队
Barn-a-cles
高中
嗨  珍珍
Hi, Pearl
我们昨晚看比赛看到你了
We saw you at the game last night
可以给我尾鳍签名吗
Will you sign my tail fin?
谢谢大家
Thanks, everybody
只是在尽我的一份力而已吧
Just doing my part, I guess
珍珍
Hey, Pearl
你在这啊
There you are
我一直都在到处找你呢
I've been looking all over for you
鳕鱼教练
Hey, Coach Cod
昨晚的事情很抱歉
Sorry about last night
我以后会尽量远离球场的
I'll try to stay off the field in the future
远离吗
Stay off?
不行  我要你上球场
No, I need you on the field
橄榄球队有你这么彪悍的队员
With a bruiser like you on the football team
肯定可以夺冠
we could win the championship
真的吗
Really?
可我热爱参加啦啦队
But I love being on the Cheer Squad
不知道能不能离开队友们
I don't know if I could leave them
上课要迟到了
I'm late for class
真对不起
Sorry about that
我跟你说什么来着
What'd I tell ya?
彪悍
A bruiser
珍珍
Pearl
真高兴你能决定加入我们
Glad you decided to join us
戴好头盔上场去
Grab a helmet and get out there on the field
训练就快开始了
Practice is just starting
那就听你的
If you say so
来给我见识一下你的本领吧
Why don't you show me what you've got?
好
Okay
那就来了
Here goes
最好从基本功开始练起
We'd better start with the basics
打橄榄球用不着蹦蹦跳跳
There's no prancing in football
要跑起来
You run
就像这样
like this
明白了
I see
好好好  跑得也差不多了
Okay, okay, that's enough running
来看看你接球的水平如何
Let's see how you are at catching the ball
第一步
Step one
是向四分卫示意自己可以接球了
is signaling to the quarterback that you're open
我能行的
I can do that
我正好有个啦啦操能引起他的注意
I have the perfect cheer to get his attention
来个橄
F-O-O
来个榄
T-B-A
再来球  比赛就这么办
L-L is the game we play
传给我
I'm open
我可以接到球
I'm O-P-E-N, open
差不多得了
That's enough
改练阻截试试
Let's try some tackling instead
队友们  撞过来吧
Okay, team, show me some hits
对
Yeah
好
Good
狠狠撞疼吧
Bring the pain
十码线
Ten-yard line
停船场线
Parking lot line
到此为止
End of the line
线
抱歉
Sorry
还好那底下有辆救护车垫着做缓冲
Good thing this ambulance was there to break my fall
好  训练结束
Okay, practice is over
谢谢大家来参加我们的啦啦队员面试
Thanks everyone
for coming to our cheerleader auditions
你们肩负上一任队员珍珍的重任
We've got some whale-sized shoes to fill
鞋
所以来看看你们有什么本领
so let's see what you've got
悲观失望
Doom and Gloom
前景灰暗
Black and Grey
希望你们今天害对手玩完
I hope you crush your foes today
那还挺
That was very
有活力
peppy?
好了  下一个
Okay, next
大家好
Hi, everyone
我是鱿鱼妹
I'm Squidina Star
我正在做一部纪录片
and I'm making a documentary
主题是加入啦啦队
about joining the cheer squad
得先绑好我的第一人称头戴式摄像头
Just need to strap on my POV camera
才能开始表演
before I start my routine
哒哒
Ta-da
我们会等纪录片发行的
I think we'll wait for the movie to come out
下一个
Next
我叫弗雷德丽卡
My name is Frederica
是来为你们加油的
and I came here to cheer you on
我的女儿好棒
That's my girl
我们是裤头村
We're Bikini Bottom
我们来大打特打
We came here to fight
今晚在橄榄球场  保证把你们打趴
We will kick your booties
on the football field tonight
等你们看到我们来
When you see us coming
就会求安全想自卫
For your safety you will beg
但你们最多只会听到我们喊出小心
But the only thing you'll hear from us is watch out for
我的腿
My leg
不好
Oh, no
弗雷德丽卡
Frederica?
我的腿
My leg
不用怕  弗雷德老表
Don't worry, Cousin Fred
我是个医生
I'm a doctor
我的腿
My leg
我来帮忙
I'll help
我的腿
My leg
让我帮忙
Let me help
我的腿
My Leg
我来救你  弗雷德
I'll help you, Fred
我的腿
My leg
应该会耗上好一阵子
This could take awhile
这边有没有谁可以正常做啦啦操的
Is there anyone who can actually do a normal cheer?
我这边这位会你们所有的啦啦操
I got someone who knows all your cheers
我们机会来了  小子
This is our chance, boy-o
你一旦加入了啦啦队  就可以
Once you make the squad, you can
在一大群观众面前表演我的啦啦操了
get my cheer in front of the masses
我懂了
I get it
加油  藤壶队
Let's go, Barnacles
啦啦啦
Rah-rah-rah
加油  藤壶队
Let's go, Barnacles
啦啦啦
Rah-rah-rah
他没断腿
Well, he didn't break his leg
他还好轻盈
And he's so light
用来到处抛还特别理想
He's a dream to throw around
可以了
That does it
欢迎加入啦啦队
Welcome to the squad
第一次正式比赛
My first official game
我好紧张
I'm so nervous
欢迎回到又一场
Welcome back to another
刺激的藤壶队橄榄球之夜
exciting evening of Barnacles Football
我是你们今晚的解说员
I'll be your announcer tonight
因为厕所是我先到的
because I made it to the bathroom first
拜托
Come on
搞什么
What gives?
有人使用
Occupied
Occupied?
球来了
The ball?
我该怎么办
What do I do?
跑
Run
珍珍有那玩意
Pearl has the thingy
可是其他人想要那玩意
but these other guys want the thingy
别被他们抢了那玩意  珍珍
Don't let them have the thingy, Pearl
全垒打
Home run
[ 棒球 ]
我爱橄榄球
I love football
触地得分
Touchdown
比赛结束
Game over
藤壶队获胜
Barnacles win
给我一个王
Gimme a P
给我一个㐱
Gimme an E
再给我来一个珍
Gimme an A-R-L
拼起来是什么人
What's it spell?
等一下  先别提醒
Hold on, don't tell me
我还在加
I'm still adding it up
珍珍
Pearl
我本来还能算出来的
I coulda done it
你在搞什么名堂  小子
What are you playin' at, boy-o?
你没做我编的蟹堡王啦啦操
You didn't do my Krusty Krab cheer
抱歉  蟹老板
Sorry, Mr. Krabs
下场比赛一定会做的  我发誓
I'll do it next game, I promise
最好给我做出来  海绵宝宝
See that you do, SpongeBob
给我做出来
See that you do
太酷了
So cool
能给我的壳签名吗
Will you sign my shell?
谢谢
Thank you
嗨  珍珍
Hi Pearl
就爱你那态度
Love the attitude
你变了好多
You've really changed
废话  我当然变了
Yeah, no duh I've changed
我是全校史上最厉害的橄榄球员
I'm the greatest football player
this school has ever seen
来吧  兄弟们
Come on, boys
开球
Hike
珍珍
Pearl
是我们的女生
She's our girl
她要是不行  我会呕吐狂喷
If she can't do it, I'll totally hurl
珍珍
Hey, Pearl
天啊  我有点担心今晚的锦标赛
Boy, I'm worried about tonight's Championship Game
拜托  教练
Come on, Coach
再来一场  我保证能再赢一场
Another game, another win
看这个视频片段  拍的是我们的对手
Take a look at this footage of our opponents
纽开普市少年犯队
The New Kelp City Delinquents
全队留级了几十年
Their entire team
纽开普市高中
has been held back in school for decades
这些家伙坏透了
These guys are bad
从鱼鳃坏到了尾鳍
I mean from their gills to their tail fins
所以也许我们还是弃赛吧
So maybe we should just forfeit
他们看着猛  只是因为没遇到我而已
They only look tough 'cause they haven't met me
好耶
Yeah
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen
有请裤头村藤壶队
your Bikini Bottom Barnacles
以及前来以工代监的
And here on a work release program
纽开普市少年犯队
The New Kelp City Delinquents
好了  队友们
Alright, team
都听好了
Come on, listen up
平常到这时候我会讲些鼓舞士气的话
Normally I'd give a pep talk right now
但我觉得现在更适合
but I think this time would be better spent
跟你们的至亲至爱告别
saying goodbye to your loved ones
手伸过来
Come on, hands in
加油  藤壶队
Let's go, Barnacles
对了  我还听说少年犯队
Oh, yeah, and I heard the Delinquents
在场上布了水雷
may have mined the field
所以你们比赛小心点
so just be careful out there
拜托  就几个水雷而已
Come on, guys, it's just a few mines
我们能行的
We can do this
一起给他们见识下我们藤壶队
Let's show 'em what Barnacles
有什么本领
are made of?
加油  藤壶队
Let's go, Barnacles
那头鲸鱼是我女儿
That whale's me daughter
一场比赛都没输过
and she's never lost a game
是吗
Oh, yeah?
那边那位是我儿子
Well, that's my boy out there
一场比赛也没输过
and he's never lost a game either
什么  他吗
What, him?
他上高中吗
He's in high school?
几年级了
What year is he?
十年刑期的第五年
Five years into a ten-year stretch
表现良好的话  第八年可能就毕业了
He might graduate in eight with good behavior
那我女儿珍珍肯定能打得他
Well, me Pearly-Girl is gonna make him
希望自己能按时毕业
wish he had graduated on time
是吗
Oh, really?
要打赌吗
Wanna bet?
好啊
Yeah
要是藤壶队赢了
If the Barnacles win
你就得给我五块钱
you gotta give me five bucks
那要是输了呢
And if they lose?
要是藤壶队会输
If the Barnacles were to lose
免费蟹黄堡给大家送出
free Krabby Patties for all of youse
什么
What?
赌就赌
I'll take that bet
海绵宝宝  你干什么
SpongeBob, what're you doin'?
那赌注可比五块钱贵多了
That's worth a whole lot more than five bucks
放心
Don't worry
还能怎么输
How could we lose?
我们队里有珍珍呢
We've got Pearl on our side
欢迎回来  藤壶呆头
Welcome back, Barnacle Heads
又到了一场精彩刺激的保龄球之夜
it's another exciting night of bowling ball
球一个大脚踢出去了
And here's the big kick
看来他找到了他们进攻方的漏洞
Looks like he found a hole in their offense
珍珍要把球踢回去
Pearl's gonna return the kick
她像赛马一样冲了出去
She's off like a racehorse
现在又像赛马一样被压扁了
And now she's being crushed like a racehorse
就算是粉身碎骨也拦不住珍珍
Pearl's not gonna let all her crushed bones stop her
好
Okay
我可能是有一点自负了
I might have been a little overconfident
但我们还能扳回一城  对吧队友们
But we can still turn it around, right, team?
各位  场上的藤壶队队员只剩珍珍了
Folks, Pearl is the only Barnacle left on the field
但他们打算让她继续比赛
but they're going to let her play on
祝你好运
Good luck to ya
他们会把我搞死的
These guys are gonna kill me
该怎么办
What do I do?
珍珍  你看着很紧张的样子
Hey, Pearl, you look nervous
我要跟你分享一个特别的啦啦操
I'm gonna share a special cheer with you
是我奶奶教我的
My grandma taught it to me
每当日子难熬  境况不畅
When days are tough and things go bad
奶奶会帮你不再悲伤
grandmas help you not feel sad
假如奶奶不在  你依然烦恼
If Gran's not here and you're still blue
别忘了做自己就好
remember to just be you
做自己就好
Just be me
对
Yeah
谢了  奶奶
Thanks, Grandma
奶奶说得对
Grandma is right
我喜欢做一个橄榄球星
I liked being a football star
但我热爱做一名啦啦队员
but I love being a cheerleader
一飞冲天
Sis-boom-bah
来个蟹
K-R-U
来个堡
S-T-Y
再来个王  正正好
K-R-A-B, my-oh-my
蟹堡王营业到很晚
The Krusty Krab is open late
来买蟹黄堡  味道赞
So buy some patties, they taste great
蟹堡王
Krusty Krab
我的啦啦操
Me cheer
她在做我编的啦啦操
She's doing me cheer
多谢你什么都没干  海绵宝宝
Thanks for nothin', SpongeBob
我们有薯条和汽水饮料
We've got fries and sody drinks
还有一件事
And one more thing
海之霸很糟糕
The Chum Bucket stinks
射门得分
Goooooal
[ 足球 ]
珍珍
Pearl
裤头村高中
主队           第4节         客队
比赛结束
Game over
少年犯队获胜
Delinquents win
大家听我说
Hey, everyone
免费蟹黄堡
Free Krabby Patties
这么重要的比赛  我竟然输了
I can't believe I lost the big game
别对自己那么苛刻  珍珍
Oh, well, don't be too hard on yourself, Pearl
那可是我们对战少年犯队的最高分
That was the best score
we've ever had against the Delinquents
我们明年一定能战胜他们的
We'll definitely get 'em next year
谢了  教练
Thanks, Coach
不过我明年不会回来参赛了
but I won't be coming back next year
今晚的事让我想起了我的第一爱好
Tonight helped me remember my first love
啦啦队
cheerleading
更何况  啦啦队还缺一个队员呢
Besides, I think there's an opening on the squad
快回来
Get back here
不是学生就不可以参加啦啦队
You can't be a cheerleader if you're not a student
不要
No
我不跑
I won't go
不要
No
我不跑
I won't go
别做啦啦操了
Stop cheering
求你不要把它从我身边夺走
Please don't take this away from me
帕奇
Perch
厕所归你了  哥们
The bathroom is yours, my man
比赛结束
Game over